<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Chino Soliard</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/all-en.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2013-08-17T19:00:00-03:00</updated><entry><title>Problems mounting NTFS partitions from Windows 8 on Fedora</title><link href="/blog/2013/ago/problems-mounting-ntfs-windows8-fedora-en.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-08-17T19:00:00-03:00</published><author><name>chinosoliard</name></author><id>tag:,2013-08-17:blog/2013/ago/problems-mounting-ntfs-windows8-fedora-en.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Windows 8 brings enabled by default “Quick Start”, this feature is for Windows to start in a time relatively short (very noticeable compared to other Windows versions), and works by making the system does not shut down completely, if that is not a state “partial” hibernation, I mean, saves the state of the system into a file on disk, and when you start the system again, load the file contents, leaving the system in the same way that when turned off.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem comes when, in my case for this example, I want to start GNU / Linux which has a configuration in / etc / fstab to automatically mount the partition I use to share data between the two operating systems, Fedora tells me that you have problems mount that partition.
The solution is simple, disable this feature in Windows, to do this …  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boot up Windows 8  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the start menu, type “power management”.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the right side menu, go to “Settings” tab.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There, select from the left menu the option “Change startup / shutdown button actions”.”&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/article/2013/08/ntfs-1.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="nfts-1" src="/images/article/2013/08/ntfs-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It opens a “System Configuration” window with some blocked options, we click “Change settings that are currently unavailable”, this will allow us to change the blocked settings.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/article/2013/08/ntfs-2.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="nfts-2" src="/images/article/2013/08/ntfs-2.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, simply uncheck the box “Enable Quick Start (recommended)” and save the changes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/article/2013/08/ntfs-3.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="nfts-3" src="/images/article/2013/08/ntfs-3.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it, now there is no problem to mount NTFS partitions of Windows 8 on GNU / Linux.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Fedora"></category><category term="GNU/Linux"></category><category term="issue"></category><category term="NTFS"></category><category term="partition"></category><category term="power"></category><category term="problem"></category><category term="Windows"></category><category term="Windows-8"></category></entry><entry><title>Synchronizing files with UNISON on Fedora</title><link href="/blog/2013/may/synchronizing-files-unison-fedora-en.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-05-22T14:00:00-03:00</published><author><name>chinosoliard</name></author><id>tag:,2013-05-22:blog/2013/may/synchronizing-files-unison-fedora-en.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Installing UNISON&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  Unison is in Fedora repositories, so, installing it is just using the following command:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;su -c ‘yum install unison’&lt;/code&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating Sinchronization profiles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  Unison works with profiles, which are configured to specify which directories are going to be synchronized.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We execute Unison, now I can’t remember if the first time it automatically ran the profile wizard to add a profile, if not, click the “Add” button to start the creation wizard.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the first screen, which is just an introduction, click on “Forward”.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/article/2013/05/unison-1.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="unison-1" src="/images/article/2013/05/unison-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, it ask us to complete the profile name and description. We complete and give next.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/article/2013/05/unison-2.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="unison-2" src="/images/article/2013/05/unison-2.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, it asks us to select the connection type, where we can choose Local, SSH, RSH and TCP.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local Sinchronization profiles&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We follow the steps above, now select “Local” from the list of connection types and give “forward”.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/article/2013/05/unison-3.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="unison-3" src="/images/article/2013/05/unison-3.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below, we declare the directories involved in the synchronization, when complete, give “Forward”.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/article/2013/05/unison-4.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="unison-4" src="/images/article/2013/05/unison-4.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my case, I’m going to synchronize directories that are on NTFS partitions, therefore, I check the box to set the profile to work without using the GNU/Linux permissions.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/article/2013/05/unison-5.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="unison-5" src="/images/article/2013/05/unison-5.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, Unison report that it finished configuring the profile, and we press “Apply” to create it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/article/2013/05/unison-6.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="unison-6" src="/images/article/2013/05/unison-6.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remote SSH Synchronization Profile&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We follow the steps above, now select “SSH” from the list of connection types, the contents of the window will be extended and now we be asked to introduce the host, which can be the name or IP address of the computer to which we want to connect, and the username that we will use to log into the host.&lt;br /&gt;
   Also, we can activate a checkbox to let Unison compress the files to be sent, as you can read at the window, is good for slow connections, but make fast connections more slower.&lt;br /&gt;
   After setting this, give next.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/article/2013/05/unison-7.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="unison-7" src="/images/article/2013/05/unison-7.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we set the directories that we will synchronize. We can select the Local directory, the remote directory should be written, so it is necessary to know first the name of the directory. You can confirm this by doing a SSH connection with a console.&lt;br /&gt;
 After that, click on “Forward”.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/article/2013/05/unison-8.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="unison-8" src="/images/article/2013/05/unison-8.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As in the previous example, where we done a Local Synchronization, we can set the profile to work with NTFS or FAT, or rather, to exclude the treatment of file permissions that GNU / Linux uses. In my case, I use NTFS partitions in sync, so I active the checkbox.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/article/2013/05/unison-9.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="unison-9" src="/images/article/2013/05/unison-9.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then just press “Apply” and it’s ready, we ended setting the profile.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/article/2013/05/unison-10.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="unison-10" src="/images/article/2013/05/unison-10.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performing a Synchronization.&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Execute a synchronization profile, selecting it from the list and clicking on “Open”.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/article/2013/05/unison-11.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="unison-11" src="/images/article/2013/05/unison-11.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;When opening one of the profiles created to synchronize via SSHwe will be asked for a password to login.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/article/2013/05/unison-12.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="unison-12" src="/images/article/2013/05/unison-12.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we did the first synchronization, it shows a window like this, which explains that there are no historical records of synchronizations, and that this is because, or synchronizations have not been performed yet, or we’ve updated the version of Unison and this one does not recognize the historical files; Wherefore, Unison assumes that the historical record is completely empty.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/article/2013/05/unison-13.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="unison-13" src="/images/article/2013/05/unison-13.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The first time you perform synchronizations, this process takes too long.&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the comparison, Unison generates a list, which automatically adjusted the changes to make, which we can modify.&lt;br /&gt;
  We review the shifts to be performed, we can skip changes (which ignores the row, it make no changes), and choose the replacement and copying in both directions.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/article/2013/05/unison-14.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="unison-14" src="/images/article/2013/05/unison-14.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we checked the changes to make, press the “Go” button, and Unison start syncing.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After finishing copying files, a window will appear reporting that the synchronization finished, and a short summary, which we can extend.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/article/2013/05/unison-15.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="unison-15" src="/images/article/2013/05/unison-15.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the simply way to use Unison; If a profile have a first run done, the point 3.2 end faster.&lt;br /&gt;
An important point to note is that Unison must be installed on both devices, if synchronization is performed remotely.  &lt;br /&gt;
n this guide we work with Unison with graphical environment, but also can be used with a console (I am considering using Unison from the command line  with “cron” for automating synchronizations and backups).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope it has served.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;regards&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Fedora"></category><category term="GNU/Linux"></category><category term="Local"></category><category term="maintenance"></category><category term="SSH"></category><category term="Sync"></category><category term="Synchronization"></category><category term="UNISON"></category></entry><entry><title>My first Fedora 18 (Spherical Cow) post after 2 weeks of use</title><link href="/blog/2013/feb/first-Fedora18-post-after-2-weeks-en.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-05T21:00:00-03:00</published><author><name>chinosoliard</name></author><id>tag:,2013-02-05:blog/2013/feb/first-Fedora18-post-after-2-weeks-en.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;To start, installation is super simple, I just didn’t like (and after trying it 4 times I don’t understand it well), is the disk partitioner, is something uncomfortable, unintuitive.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;System speed is phenomenal, and personally, it’s nice to know that there are very regular updates.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GNOME 3.6 is the bad that brought Fedora 18, and after reading some reviews noted that people have not been able to distinguish between Fedora and GNOME. Version 3.6 of GNOME is fast, the new menu, which is not much different, is good, is a change that is not feeling, but the bottom bar is not so nice as before, is larger and more sensitive, it open all the time and lock the screen. The most uncomfortable thing I’ve found is Nautilus (the file browser), I can not open two panels at a time (function which was done with the F3 key), therefore I can not drag with the middle mouse button to do links, etc., and the worst part is not being able to return to the previous folder by pressing the “Backspace”, is super uncomfortable, you have to use the mouse with Nautilus, which has greatly reduced my browsing speed.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything else has worked deluxe, although, I admit I didn’t have had much time to try other things. These contras only have reduced the time for some things, the system is still very fast and useful, and I hope GNOME people think in this errors they have had and fix them. Maybe later I make another post about the subject. Now I get to continue programming.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regards!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Fedora"></category><category term="Fedora-18"></category><category term="GNOME"></category><category term="gnome-3.6"></category><category term="GNU/Linux"></category><category term="Spherical Cow"></category></entry><entry><title>Samsung printers on Fedora</title><link href="/blog/2012/oct/samsung-printer-on-fedora-en.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-10-21T19:00:00-03:00</published><author><name>chinosoliard</name></author><id>tag:,2012-10-21:blog/2012/oct/samsung-printer-on-fedora-en.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first (and no functional) option was install the &lt;a href="http://downloadcenter.samsung.com/content/DR/200911/20091118145015140/UnifiedLinuxDriver_1.01.tar.gz"&gt;Samsung Unified Linux Drivers&lt;/a&gt;, I executed the installer with “$ sudo” and start the installation. During the installation, it’s possible installing printers, I plug the ML-1640, and everything looks to be right. When I finished the installation, I go to CUPS page (&lt;a href="http://localhost:631/"&gt;http://localhost:631&lt;/a&gt;) and the printer were on the list. Among many details that I can’t remember, all I know is that the printer never worked, I searched the Internet and found that the package was very problematic, then I want to uninstall the package, for this, in a console run $ sudo / opt / Samsung / mfp / uninstall / guiuninstall, this will start the uninstallation. After a few steps, the program did not leave traces (or it seems).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second (and functional), and simpler, is installing Splix, a set of CUPS drivers that handle SPL (Samsung Printer Language). Following, I explain how I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now is packaged for Fedora, so, all you have to do to install the package is run in a console 
  &lt;code&gt;$ sudo yum install splix&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After installing Splix, just connect the printer (windows appear to install drivers, but cancel) and go to CUPS (http://localhost:631), once in CUPS, we go to Administration, and then to “Add printer “.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The printer appears connected in the list of local printers, select it and press “next”. 
&lt;a href="/images/article/2012/10/samsung-printer-on-fedora-1.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="samsung-printer-on-fedora-1" src="/images/article/2012/10/samsung-printer-on-fedora-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After, configurations for printer name, description, location, and the option of sharing appears; We click on “next” (after set the fields to taste).
&lt;a href="/images/article/2012/10/samsung-printer-on-fedora-2.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="samsung-printer-on-fedora-2" src="/images/article/2012/10/samsung-printer-on-fedora-2.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got to the step where we define the controller, in the list “Model” select the model you are installing, then “Add Printer”.
&lt;a href="/images/article/2012/10/samsung-printer-on-fedora-3.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="samsung-printer-on-fedora-3" src="/images/article/2012/10/samsung-printer-on-fedora-3.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we are asked to establish the default options for the printer
&lt;a href="/images/article/2012/10/samsung-printer-on-fedora-4.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="samsung-printer-on-fedora-4" src="/images/article/2012/10/samsung-printer-on-fedora-4.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we are in the printer’s page in CUPS, we can test the printer selecting “Print Test Page” in the “Maintenance” menu.
&lt;a href="/images/article/2012/10/samsung-printer-on-fedora-5.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="samsung-printer-on-fedora-5" src="/images/article/2012/10/samsung-printer-on-fedora-5.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The printer is working, but, to me personally, four printers appear installed on the CUPS printer list, so I removed the ones I didn’t install (detected by the name).
&lt;a href="/images/article/2012/10/samsung-printer-on-fedora-6.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="samsung-printer-on-fedora-6" src="/images/article/2012/10/samsung-printer-on-fedora-6.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that’s the simply way to install the printers, I hope you have been useful.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CLP-315"></category><category term="CUPS"></category><category term="Fedora"></category><category term="GNU/Linux"></category><category term="printer"></category><category term="ML-1640"></category><category term="samsung"></category><category term="Samsung Unified Linux Driver"></category><category term="SPLIX"></category></entry><entry><title>New project = Airlife100.com.ar</title><link href="/blog/2012/sep/project-airlife100comar-en.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-28T00:00:00-03:00</published><author><name>chinosoliard</name></author><id>tag:,2012-09-28:blog/2012/sep/project-airlife100comar-en.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="Airlife100"></category><category term="Android"></category><category term="project"></category></entry><entry><title>Programmer Day</title><link href="/blog/2012/sep/programmer-day-2012-en.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-12T14:00:00-03:00</published><author><name>chinosoliard</name></author><id>tag:,2012-09-12:blog/2012/sep/programmer-day-2012-en.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why the day 256?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It was chosen because it is the number of different combinations that can be represented with 8 bits, number well known among programmers. It is also the largest power of 2 less than 365, the number of days a year.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="ProgrammerDay" src="http://www.programmerday.info/images/header.jpg" title="ProgrammerDay" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programming today is a race between software engineers striving to build bigger and better idiot-proof programs, and the Universe trying to produce bigger and better idiots. So far, the Universe is winning. - Rick Cook  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Happy programmer day!&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Dirty computers, dust inside</title><link href="/blog/2012/sep/dirty-computer-dust-inside-en.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-05T14:00:00-03:00</published><author><name>chinosoliard</name></author><id>tag:,2012-09-05:blog/2012/sep/dirty-computer-dust-inside-en.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cleaning the inside of the CPU is something that should be done routinely to prevent problems become greater, because when dust accumulates, it is only a matter of moisture to a short circuit, for example.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="maintenance"></category></entry></feed>