<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Chino Soliard - Projects</title><link href="https://www.chinosoliard.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="feeds//feeds/atom/category-projects.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://www.chinosoliard.com/</id><updated>2016-04-14T14:20:00-03:00</updated><entry><title>Migrando a Pelican</title><link href="https://www.chinosoliard.com/blog/2016/abr/moving-to-pelican-es.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-14T14:20:00-03:00</published><author><name>chinosoliard</name></author><id>tag:www.chinosoliard.com,2016-04-14:/blog/2016/abr/moving-to-pelican-es.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.getpelican.com" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img alt="pelican" src="/images/article/2016/04/pelican.png" class="alignright"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Después de unos meses haciendo trabajo de hormiga, ya casi he terminado de migrar mi sitio a &lt;a href="http://www.getpelican.com"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Pelican es un poderoso generador de sitios webs estáticos, está escrito en Python, por lo cual, está en constante avance.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Pelican"></category><category term="web"></category><category term="GNU/Linux"></category><category term="Project"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>New project = Airlife100.com.ar</title><link href="https://www.chinosoliard.com/blog/2012/sep/project-airlife100comar-en.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-28T00:00:00-03:00</published><author><name>chinosoliard</name></author><id>tag:www.chinosoliard.com,2012-09-28:/blog/2012/sep/project-airlife100comar-en.html/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last year, anxiety, trouble and ignorance made me buy a tablet that has a spectacular look, and some features that for the time were very good, the Airlife 100 by HP Compaq.&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Just out of the box, I loved it. White, light, nice and tiny, very promising. When I started to explore the Android system that it had, I noticed that it was not what I knew (I had met Android in a friend’s Motorola Milestone)&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;It turns out that this tablet brings Android 1.6, but for the worse (as always seems to happen with these privative companies) is not an ordinary Android system, it has limitations that prohibit you (among other things) access the official Android Market, and even, if I had the APK to install the applications, many can not be installed.&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;The product (as expected) had little market impact, all it got were complaints, then I started to find out what could be done.&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;I read many publications on some pages and it seems that there are many people who want to do something with this tablet, my idea is join all these people to work together to make this tablet more functional.&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Anyway, the project website is &lt;a href="http://www.airlife100.com.ar"&gt;http://www.airlife100.com.ar&lt;/a&gt;, it’s still under construction, but I hope to achieve my goal&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Airlife100"></category><category term="Android"></category><category term="project"></category></entry></feed>